NIKUNJ RATHOD

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER · . NET

 $(+1)\ 506-875-7033\ |\ \underline{nikunjrathod3011@gmail.com}\ |\ \underline{nikunj3011.github.io}\ |\ Github-\underline{nikunj3011}\ |\ LinkedIn-\underline{nikunj3011}$

Summary_

3+ years' experience specializing in software design, analysis, development, testing and implementation of web and client server applications and cloud technologies. Dedicated worker with quick learning and integration with development teams. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Technical Strengths

LANGUAGES: C#, VB.net, JavaScript , Java, Python, C++

Frameworks: ASP.Net Core, React, Android **DATABASE:** RDBMS, SQL server, MySQL

WEB: HTML5, Syncfusion, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, JSON, XML, Selenium, REST and SOAP web services

CLOUD: Azure, Bitbucket, GitHub, Git, Docker, Kubernetes

Others: JIRA, Samsara, SYSPRO, Postman, Unit Testing, Agile/Scrum methodology, Visual Studio, MVC, MVVM, Entity Framework

Industry Experience _____

Ditech Testing Scoudouc, NB, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Apr. 2021 - Current

- Experience working in Propane Tank Refurbishing company, interact with companies employee and management.
- Analyze, design, develop, code, and implement programs in one or more programming languages, for Web and Desktop Internet Application.
- Worked with .NET Core, VB.Net, Visual Studio, Entity Framework, Web API, SignalR, SQL Server, SYNCFUSION, HTML5, JavaScript, React, LINQ, Git, Agile.
- Develop .Net Core N-tier API applications as well as web applications using .NET MVC, REACT, SYNCFUSION, JQUERY and JAVA SCRIPT.
- Experience with third party ERP system, Fleet management and integrating it with company data.
- Provided database connectivity using Entity Framework, LINQ, designed stored procedures and views at the back end.
- Experience working with cloud infrastructure utilizing Azure, Docker, and Kubernetes.
- Worked in Agile Scrum methodology and delivered accepted functionality in each sprint.
- Provide guidance to non-technical staff on how to use software and hardware systems most effectively and efficiently.

Hari Skyline Ahmedabad, Gujarat, INDIA

Intern DEVELOPER

Nov. 2018 - July. 2019

- Experience with development of REST API using Asp.net Core.
- Use Rest API in Unity game for an online game.
- Experience with design patterns.
- Expert in debugging an application using debugging tools provided by Visual Studio.
- Debugging and testing the game.

Education

B.TECH (IT)

Changa, Gujarat, INDIA

Charotar University of Science and Technology Sep. 2015-Apr. 2019

IT: Software Experience Development

Moncton, NB, Canada

Sep. 2019-Apr. 2021

Projects

New Brunswick Community College

ASP.net Game Web App on AZURE

Proiect

Developed ASP.net Web application using SQL server database deployed on Azure. MVC and microservices architecture. Basic Bearer Authentication. Also used buckets to host static website and images for the website. Moreover, used SignalR for real-time data. RabbitMQ for ASYNCHRONOUS MESSAGING and GRPC for SYNCHRONOUS MESSAGING. Used Docker and Kubernetes to make it scalable and deploy it. Terraform with Azure for laac.

Clash Royal Stickers (Google Play)

Project

Developed Clash Royal Stickers app (android studio) and published it on google play. Google Admob to display ads.

Certifications

Certified Kubernetes Application Developer (CKAD)
Certified Kubernetes Administrator (CKA)

NIKUNJ RATHOD · RESUME